

ABOUT ME

Hi, my name is Matt Callahan and I am a software engineer in Phoenix, Arizona. I have over ten years of experience in web, desktop, and GIS/map application development. Learning the ever-changing landscape of software development is my passion.

CONTACT

EMAIL:

matthew.callahan@outlook.com

PHONE:

630-988-1555

HOMEPAGE:

mfcallahan.com

LINKEDIN:

linkedin.com/in/mfcallahan1

GITHUB:

github.com/mfcallahan

CERTIFICATIONS

Microsoft Technology Associate: Developer

KEY SKILLS

C# (.NET & .NET Core) JavaScript ES6+ TypeScript Angular Node.js Python Git

ArcGIS

Backend & API development Cloud app deployment

MATTHEW CALLAHAN

EDUCATION



University of Wisconsin–Madison

Bachelor of Science, Geographic Information Science

EXPERIENCE

Staff Engineer, Republic Services | Scottsdale, Arizona

May 2019 - Present

- Lead a team of nine developers and testers, overseeing talent development, skill set improvement, and acting as a mentor to all team members.
- Established and implemented a standard application architecture (.NET & .NET Core back end/Angular front end).
- Implemented unit test standards for the team and led effort to increase test coverage on all apps, reducing the number of production bugs.
- Authored coding conventions and style guide documents for developers and currently leading effort to refactor all applications to follow these guidelines.

Senior GIS Developer, Republic Services | Scottsdale, Arizona December 2019 – May 2019

- Front and back end web development, creating enterprise applications which focused on mapping and visualizing data to assist in daily business operations (ASP.NET, Angular).
- Desktop GIS application development (ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, Python).
- Implemented a uniform Git branching strategy and code review process for all application repositories.

Software Engineer, Carvana | Tempe, Arizona

February 2018 - December 2019

- Back end development to create and maintain the APIs and applications which powered carvana.com (C#, .NET & .NET Core).
- Front end development to create a mobile responsive vehicle inventory search engine user interface (JS ES6+, React/Redux, AngularJS).
- Implemented A/B testing to help drive data analytics and deliver best UX.

Application Developer, CBRE | Phoenix, Arizona

January 2011 - February 2018

- Developed web applications which provided analytical and mapping tools to real estate brokers and their clients (ASP.NET MVC).
- Administered on-premises web and SQL servers (Windows Server, IIS, SQL Server, ArcGIS Server).
- Developed desktop applications for GIS data analysis (C# .NET, WinForms, MapBasic, ArcGIS Pro .NET SDK, Python).
- Employee of the year "MVP" award, 2012.

GIS Technician, CBRE | Phoenix, Arizona

March 2008 - January 2011

- Developed scripts and desktop GIS tools to automate tasks and improve workflow efficiency of GIS Technicians.
- Created custom maps, demographic reports, and market research reports for commercial real estate brokers, affording them the ability to make well informed decisions and best serve their clients.
- Employee of the Quarter, 1st guarter 2009.